Guide to the Stanford University, Cabinet, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Cabinet, records
1990-2013
SC0602
Stanford University. Cabinet.
13.5 Linear feet and megabytes
Agenda, minutes, memoranda, reports, and other records, 1990-1996.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfers, 1999-2000.
Information about Access
RESTRICTED FOR 20 YEARS FROM MEETING DATE
Biographical/Historical note
The primary function of the University Cabinet is to recommend and review principles, policies, and rules of University-wide significance. Chaired by the President, membership of the Executive Cabinet includes the Provost, Deans of the seven Schools, the Vice Provost and Dean of Research, the Director of the Stanford Linear Accelerator Center, the Director of the Hoover Institution, the Vice Provost for Undergraduate Education, and the Vice Provost for Graduate Education. Its purpose is to assure the centrality of academic objectives in the work of the University. Membership of the Full Cabinet includes the Executive Cabinet, the Vice Presidents, and other senior administrators and invited officers. The President and the Provost seek the Full Cabinet's advice on issues of University direction, policy, and planning, including, but not limited to: long-range planning for faculty and academic program development; strategic planning on financial, facilities, and fund-raising matters; faculty and student affairs; and personnel policies. The Cabinet advises the President and the Provost on other matters as appropriate.
Description of the Collection
Agenda, minutes, memoranda, reports, and other records, 1990-1996.
Access Terms
Stanford University -- General subdivision--Administration.;; Stanford University. Cabinet.
Collection Contents
- Records
  - Agenda, minutes, memoranda, reports, and other records, Oct. 1990 – Aug. 1991 (3 binders) (Box 1)
  - Agenda, minutes, memoranda, reports, and other records, Sept. 1991 –Apr. 1992 (3 binders) (Box 2)
  - Agenda, minutes, memoranda, reports, and other records, May 1992 – Dec. 1992 (3 binders) (Box 3)
  - Agenda, minutes, memoranda, reports, and other records, Jan. – Dec. 1992 (3 binders) (Box 4)
  - Agenda, minutes, memoranda, reports, and other records, Jan. – Aug. 1994; and Notes 1992-94 (2 binders) (Box 5)
  - Agenda, minutes, memoranda, reports, and other records, 1995-1996 (3 binders) (Box 6)
- Records, Accession ARCH-1999-267
  - Agenda, minutes, memoranda, and supporting documents for meetings October 17, 1990-March 5, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Agenda, minutes, memoranda, and supporting documents for meetings March 18, 1992-December 1994 (Box 2)
  - Planning reports on academic and administrative issues for meetings of the Cabinet Committee on Budget and Strategic Planning, August and September 1991 (Box 3)
- Computer files, 2005-2013; Accession ARCH-2013-041
  - 2005 Jan 14
  - 2005 Mar 17
  - 2005 May 12
  - 2005 Sep 15
  - 2005 Nov 11
  - 2006 Jan 19
  - 2006 Mar 16
  - 2006 May 18
  - 2006 Sep 14
  - 2006 Nov 9
  - 2007 Jan 18
  - 2007 Mar 22
  - 2007 May 17
  - 2007 Sep 12
  - 2007 Nov 8
  - 2008 Jan 17
  - 2008 Mar 13
  - 2008 May 15
  - 2008 Sep 18
  - 2008 Nov 13
  - 2009 Jan 15
  - 2009 Mar 19
  - 2009 May 14
  - 2009 Sep 17
  - 2009 Nov 12
  - 2010 Apr 1
  - 2010 May 13
  - 2010 Sep 16
  - 2010 Nov 11
  - 2011 Jan 13
  - 2011 Mar 10
  - 2011 May 12
  - 2011 Sep 15
  - 2011 Nov 8
  - 2012 Jan 12
  - 2012 Mar 8
  - 2012 May 17
  - 2012 Sep 20
  - 2012 Nov 8
  - 2013 Jan 17
  - 2013 Mar 14